foreign
house surrounded by a forest of
evergreens
home to all manner of creatures from
gentle black bears to
Humble Downy woodpeckers
I consider many of the Pines my friends
they're excellent listeners and teach me
that peace is simply being not forcing
feelings of Joy or ignoring difficult
questions
it's embracing your story and in that
acceptance finding a sort of relief
knowing that honoring your feelings
makes you very much alive and fully
present and today I'm celebrating life
to dedicating time to Simply Having Fun
[Music]
foreign
January has been a month of
transformation I've done my best to not
be avoidant in regards to how I feel
particularly when it comes to more
uncomfortable questions
strangely enough I've found myself
reflecting on the fact that in the
scheme of things I will only be here in
my present state for a short time
I don't know how long and there is so
much out of my control and I think that
so far has been the key to becoming more
peaceful it's not avoiding big questions
or the feelings they arise it's being
fully aware of them
Mr experienced a long battle with
depression and those years partly
inspired her to become a counselor today
when I speak to her about feeling
anxious and my tendency to overwork she
encourages me to sit with how I feel and
to address the fear of the unknown my
fear of myself
I'm sometimes afraid I'm not doing
enough to leave the world a better place
and sometimes I fear I'm doing too much
and not slowing down enough to be in the
moment
I'm afraid of the Ultimate Reality that
my life is fleeting and that I need to
cultivate the life I love not wait for
it to happen
I don't know the answers to all the
secrets of the world and Beyond I don't
know a lot of things but eventually I
just might find out and that's a journey
worth pursuing I think
thank you
[Music]
foreign
all of these fears come down to a wish
to control something that by its very
nature cannot and I know deep down that
that wonder and mystery is what makes it
all matter that much more
foreign if there is one piece of advice
I can pass on from my lovely sister to
you is to not be afraid she was able to
manage and transform her mental health
when she began letting herself feel pain
love hope it was overwhelming at first
difficult but it pushed her to connect
she now says she's neither extremely
happy nor unhappy in her daily life
she acknowledges her strong emotions
when they arise and in the meantime
accepts that she's quietly content with
how things are and that is enough
her journey brought her to a deeply
spiritual place I don't know if that
would be the same for you but I can
assure you that when you open your heart
life may surprise you in unexpected ways
and take you somewhere truly astonishing
[Music]
foreign
I have gone ahead and wrapped myself in
a blanket because it is quite cold
I have such a low tolerance for the cold
it is absolutely ridiculous it isn't
just psychological though it's um like I
every year I get chill bains no matter
how many pairs of socks I wear how many
hot pads I keep in my shoes I just I
don't know why this just can't function
apparently it's been a very quiet day
I've also been feeding the birds and my
mother has so many bird feeders all
around this one tree in front of the
house and there are all types of
chickadees and Stellar Jays and Pine
siskins and even a variety of squirrels
and Chipmunks We have a family of quail
that come visit and eat a lot of the
food and it's quite funny to see around
the valley how all the quail get quite
slim during the winter but this one
family that lives right next to the
house with all these bird feeders gets
quite rotund they get very poof for you
by the end of winter they're eating very
well January has been a challenging
month but I think a good one I found
myself a bit cooped up sometimes but I
have been using that time in order to
journal and to reflect and to read quite
a few books on topics that I've been
meaning to read lately some were on
books for helping people like myself who
have found themselves struggling to let
go of work and that is uh something that
I've made multiple videos on in the past
and I have improved upon greatly but
there is still so much room for
improvement and it is interesting
because in a book that I was reading
lately they mentioned about how
important it is to let go of control
that that is something that so many of
us want to feel in regards to our own
lives we want to feel as if we have
control over all of it
and of course we do have control in the
way that we react to events and for
myself and I know for many people there
are often you know small sustainable
changes you can make in order to improve
your day and your experience however we
don't really have control over what
happens to us sometimes and there are so
many things in life that we will never
have control on and I think that I have
been in the past quite avoidant with a
lot of those feelings and questions and
I think now especially reading a lot
about these topics of Letting Go and
understanding the impermanence of life
and I have found that instead of
avoiding these emotions of the reality
of our lack of control in many things in
life I know there was a time in my life
when I found it difficult to fall asleep
because letting go of control and
relaxing my body and allowing myself to
sleep
was quite difficult and I think that is
very telling because even if you have no
trouble falling asleep sometimes I know
that many of us if not all of us like to
feel a sense of control in our lives and
these things might seem scary but I
think that the less we avoid them and
the more we really talk about them and
connect over them and in a way the
beauty of the things that unite us I
find so healing especially in terms of
learning how to enjoy today over always
thinking about tomorrow and of course
embracing working hard and working
towards your goals if you so wish but
also remembering what really matters at
the end of the day and making sure
you're nurturing those things and those
relationships we cannot control
everything we don't know how much time
we have here to connect and to love and
to be kind and thoughtful and live the
way we wish to live we might as well
start imbuing aspects of that into our
daily life even if our situation is not
perfect I'm gonna go keep reading Frog
and Toad and Wind in the Willows and
mother Westwind and all these books I
grew up with and realized that I aspired
to a life living in a little fairy house
on a riverbank and spending time with
all the Woodland creatures all day long
and getting into Mischief with them
sending all of you my love do take care
of yourselves and I will see you so very
soon
[Music]
foreign